<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog</id>
    <title>Seatsurfing Blog</title>
    <updated>2025-12-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Seatsurfing Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://seatsurfing.io/de/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[December '25 news]]></title>
        <id>https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/news-december-2025</id>
        <link href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/news-december-2025"/>
        <updated>2025-12-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In December we shipped a set of updates aimed at better usability, clearer admin controls, more transparency, and core stability improvements. Most changes came in the final week of the year, and all are available in the GitHub Releases history.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In December we shipped a set of updates aimed at better usability, clearer admin controls, more transparency, and core stability improvements. Most changes came in the final week of the year, and all are available in the GitHub Releases history.</p>
<p><strong>🗓 Better Booking Experience</strong></p>
<ul>
<li class=""><strong>Calendar view added to “My Bookings”:</strong> Users now see their bookings in a calendar layout, making it easier to scan multiple dates and times.</li>
<li class=""><strong>Improved date/time picker:</strong> The date/time selector across the UI now uses a refined Flatpickr implementation for smoother interactions.</li>
<li class=""><strong>Current filter shown in Admin Booking UI:</strong> Admins get clearer context about what bookings are being displayed rather than guessing which filters are applied.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>📧 Email Transparency and Confirmations</strong></p>
<ul>
<li class=""><strong>Email log introduced:</strong> Admins can now track sent emails, improving visibility into system communications.</li>
<li class=""><strong>Confirmation mail for organization deletion:</strong> When an org is deleted, a confirmation email will be sent — adding a safety feedback loop.</li>
<li class=""><strong>Improved email recipient names:</strong> Emails now show clearer recipient details for better context.</li>
<li class=""><strong>Mail log callback fix for ACS:</strong> Resolved an issue where the mail log wasn’t invoked when using Azure Communication Services (ACS).</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>⚙️ Booking Rules &amp; Admin Controls</strong></p>
<ul>
<li class=""><strong>Recurring bookings toggle:</strong> Admins can enable or disable recurring bookings via configuration, reducing unwanted repeats.</li>
<li class=""><strong>Optional booking approver notifications:</strong> You decide whether approvers get notified about new pending bookings.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>🧠 Clarity and Feedback in the UI</strong></p>
<ul>
<li class=""><strong>Error improvement when booking in the past:</strong> A clearer error code is provided if someone tries to create a booking in the past.</li>
<li class=""><strong>Show org language &amp; primary contact on settings page:</strong> Admin settings now surface organization language and main contact info.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>🔧 Bug Fixes and Dependency Hygiene</strong></p>
<p>December releases also included:</p>
<ul>
<li class="">Translation fixes (e.g., German strings).</li>
<li class="">Dependency bumps across UI and backend modules to keep libraries up to date.</li>
<li class="">Fix for panic when user/org deleted but token still valid.</li>
</ul>
<p>These don’t change workflows directly but reduce friction and unexpected errors.</p>
<p><strong>What This Means for You</strong></p>
<ul>
<li class="">You get <em>more clarity</em> on your bookings and communications.</li>
<li class="">Admins now have <em>tighter control</em> over rules like recurring booking and approver notifications.</li>
<li class="">UX feels <em>more polished</em>, with fewer rough edges when selecting dates or managing filters.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>📋 More details</strong></p>
<p>As always, you can find detailed information about all recent releases and technical changes on our <a href="https://github.com/seatsurfing/seatsurfing/releases" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">GitHub releases page</a>.</p>
<p><em>Ready to transform your workplace with smart desk booking? <a class="" href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/sign-up">Get started with Seatsurfing today for free</a> or <a class="" href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/contact">get in touch with us</a>.</em></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Heiner</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/virtualzone</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="news" term="news"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[November '25 news]]></title>
        <id>https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/news-november-2025</id>
        <link href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/news-november-2025"/>
        <updated>2025-12-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We've been hard at work enhancing the Seatsurfing platform throughout the past few weeks. Along with numerous bug fixes and performance improvements, we've introduced several powerful features designed to improve booking management, streamline administrative workflows, and provide better integration capabilities. Here's what's new:]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We've been hard at work enhancing the Seatsurfing platform throughout the past few weeks. Along with numerous bug fixes and performance improvements, we've introduced several powerful features designed to improve booking management, streamline administrative workflows, and provide better integration capabilities. Here's what's new:</p>
<p><strong>📧 Enhanced confirmation emails for recurring bookings</strong></p>
<p>We've significantly improved the booking experience for recurring reservations. When you create a recurring booking, you'll now receive a comprehensive confirmation email that includes iCal attachments for all booking dates.</p>
<p><strong>🗂️ Automatic booking retention management</strong></p>
<p>Organization administrators now have fine-grained control over booking data retention. We've introduced configurable retention settings that allow you to automatically delete old bookings after a specified number of days. This feature helps keep your booking database clean and manageable while ensuring compliance with data retention policies.</p>
<p><strong>ℹ️ Area information at your fingertips</strong></p>
<p>We've added quick access to area details in the booking overview. Simply click the area's info button to view the area's description and timezone. This makes it easier to understand the context of your bookings without navigating away from the overview.</p>
<p><strong>👤 Set user names from IDP</strong></p>
<p>Integration with your identity provider (IDP) just got better. Administrators can now configure Seatsurfing to automatically set users' first and last names directly from your IDP.</p>
<p><strong>💬 Improved existing booking popup</strong></p>
<p>We've updated the popup with clearer information that appears when you attempt to book a space that's already reserved.</p>
<p><strong>🔧 Administrator enhancements</strong></p>
<p>For organization administrators, we've rolled out several minor enhancements to streamline user and area management:</p>
<ul>
<li class="">Improved date time picker</li>
<li class="">Display both first and last names in the user overview</li>
<li class="">Clickable booking deeplinks for areas and spaces</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>📋 More details</strong></p>
<p>As always, you can find detailed information about all recent releases and technical changes on our <a href="https://github.com/seatsurfing/seatsurfing/releases" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">GitHub releases page</a>.</p>
<p><em>Ready to transform your workplace with smart desk booking? <a class="" href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/sign-up">Get started with Seatsurfing today for free</a> or <a class="" href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/contact">get in touch with us</a>.</em></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jan</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/janjonas</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="news" term="news"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[inki, the wireless e-paper display for Seatsurfing]]></title>
        <id>https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/inki-epaper-display</id>
        <link href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/inki-epaper-display"/>
        <updated>2025-11-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re thrilled to shine a spotlight on an open-source project closely integrated with Seatsurfing — inki, developed by the maintainer c0de111. inki is a Community-developed software which brings live seating and room-booking data from Seatsurfing directly to your office walls — and it does so with elegance, sustainability, and very little maintenance.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We’re thrilled to shine a spotlight on an open-source project closely integrated with Seatsurfing — <strong>inki</strong>, developed by the maintainer c0de111. <a href="https://c0de111.github.io/inki/seatsurfing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">inki</a> is a Community-developed software which brings live seating and room-booking data from Seatsurfing directly to your office walls — and it does so with elegance, sustainability, and very little maintenance.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="what-is-inki">What is inki?<a href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/inki-epaper-display#what-is-inki" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur What is inki?" title="Direkter Link zur What is inki?" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://c0de111.github.io/inki/seatsurfing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">inki</a> is a software for bare-metal systems like the Raspberry Pi Pico W, designed specifically for low-power operation. It wakes up periodically via a real-time clock (RTC), fetches data via Wi-Fi (e.g., from Seatsurfing’s REST API), displays that information on an e-paper screen, and then powers itself down — all autonomously.</p>
<p>The project supports two e-paper sizes — <strong>4.2"</strong> and <strong>7.5"</strong>, allowing you to choose the form factor that best fits your space.
Because e-paper retains its content even when unpowered, the display remains readable without consuming power.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://seatsurfing.io/de/assets/images/inki1-473e21ed7902dcbf539cef50d741ee35.jpg" width="1024" height="897" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="why-its-a-perfect-fit-for-seatsurfing">Why it’s a perfect fit for Seatsurfing<a href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/inki-epaper-display#why-its-a-perfect-fit-for-seatsurfing" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur Why it’s a perfect fit for Seatsurfing" title="Direkter Link zur Why it’s a perfect fit for Seatsurfing" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<ul>
<li class=""><strong>Live desk &amp; room status:</strong> Once configured, inki queries your Seatsurfing server to pull the current booking status (who is sitting where, which rooms are occupied, etc.) and displays it cleanly on the screen.</li>
<li class=""><strong>Browser-based setup:</strong> You configure inki via its own Wi-Fi access point. Point your browser to the setup page, enter your Seatsurfing API credentials (such as service account, space IDs), and you’re ready to go — no cables, no USB programmers.</li>
<li class=""><strong>Logo &amp; branding:</strong> You can even upload a custom logo or pictogram to be shown on the e-paper – making the display match your company’s visual identity.</li>
<li class=""><strong>Low maintenance:</strong> Thanks to the RTC-based power control, the device can run for thousands of update cycles on simple AA or AAA batteries.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="key-technical-features">Key technical features<a href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/inki-epaper-display#key-technical-features" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur Key technical features" title="Direkter Link zur Key technical features" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<ul>
<li class=""><strong>Ultra-low power:</strong> Uses a DS3231 RTC and a MOSFET circuit so that the Pico W is completely unpowered between wake-ups, drawing only micro-amperes.</li>
<li class=""><strong>Wireless updates:</strong> Firmware updates are done over the air. Just connect to the inki Wi-Fi, upload the new firmware via browser, and reboot.</li>
<li class=""><strong>Multiple pages:</strong> inki supports up to 8 configurable “pages” that users can cycle through using onboard buttons — e.g., room occupancy, “Do Not Disturb,” device info, and more.</li>
<li class=""><strong>Hardware &amp; open source:</strong> The project provides full hardware design files (PCB, 3D-printed enclosure), firmware (C code), and documentation under open-source licenses.</li>
</ul>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://seatsurfing.io/de/assets/images/inki2-48425f61d12562fc740d6a35e5e263b1.jpg" width="1024" height="764" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="real-world-use-cases">Real-world use cases<a href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/inki-epaper-display#real-world-use-cases" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur Real-world use cases" title="Direkter Link zur Real-world use cases" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<ul>
<li class=""><strong>Room signage:</strong> Mount inki outside meeting rooms to display real-time status (free, occupied, meeting name) pulled from Seatsurfing.</li>
<li class=""><strong>Desk sharing boards:</strong> Use in open offices to give a live visual overview of who is sitting where.</li>
<li class=""><strong>Beyond booking:</strong> Thanks to its modular firmware, inki can be repurposed for other data-display roles — for example, visualizing live sensor data from home automation systems (e.g., Homematic/CCU Historian).</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="why-we-love-it">Why we love it<a href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/inki-epaper-display#why-we-love-it" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur Why we love it" title="Direkter Link zur Why we love it" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p><a href="https://c0de111.github.io/inki/seatsurfing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">inki</a> embodies the principles of simplicity, efficiency, and practicality — qualities that resonate deeply with Seatsurfing’s mission. By combining ultra-low power hardware with a smart software design, it creates a seamless, tangible way to connect digital booking data with physical space. inki achieves this by using the documented REST APIs provided by Seatsurfing's open source project. It’s exactly the kind of community-driven innovation we hoped for when we open-sourced Seatsurfing.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="getting-started">Getting started<a href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/inki-epaper-display#getting-started" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur Getting started" title="Direkter Link zur Getting started" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>If you’re interested in using inki with your Seatsurfing instance:</p>
<ol>
<li class="">Visit the inki project website: <a href="https://c0de111.github.io/inki/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">c0de111.github.io/inki</a></li>
<li class="">Download the inki_seatsurfing.uf2 firmware from the GitHub repository.</li>
<li class="">Flash it onto a Pico W, set it up via its Wi-Fi interface, configure Seatsurfing API credentials, and select your space ID.</li>
<li class="">Insert batteries, mount the device, and enjoy a live status display that literally runs for years.</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="a-big-thanks-to-the-creator">A big thanks to the creator<a href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/inki-epaper-display#a-big-thanks-to-the-creator" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur A big thanks to the creator" title="Direkter Link zur A big thanks to the creator" translate="no">​</a></h2>
<p>We’d like to express our deep gratitude to <a href="https://github.com/c0de111" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">c0de111</a> for building this neat integration. Projects like inki make the Seatsurfing ecosystem richer — they bridge the gap between the digital booking world and physical reality, in a way that feels intuitive and elegant. ❤️</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://seatsurfing.io/de/assets/images/inki3-a550a072a686a141178608768bc5b692.jpg" width="1024" height="683" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Heiner</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/virtualzone</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="news" term="news"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[October '25 news]]></title>
        <id>https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/news-october-2025</id>
        <link href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/news-october-2025"/>
        <updated>2025-10-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We've been busy shipping improvements to the Seatsurfing platform over the past few weeks. Alongside numerous bug fixes and smaller enhancements, we've rolled out several features that focus on enhancing the user experience and giving administrators more control and flexibility. Here are the most important updates:]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We've been busy shipping improvements to the Seatsurfing platform over the past few weeks. Alongside numerous bug fixes and smaller enhancements, we've rolled out several features that focus on enhancing the user experience and giving administrators more control and flexibility. Here are the most important updates:</p>
<p><strong>📧 Improved notification emails</strong></p>
<p>We've enhanced our booking notification emails to provide more context at a glance. Email notifications for approved, modified, or deleted bookings now include the booking subject (when available), making it easier to identify which booking the notification refers to without having to open the full details.</p>
<p><strong>🌐 Localization enhancements</strong></p>
<p>The booking overview now offers more flexibility when it comes to language preferences. You can now change the localization directly within the booking overview, and we've added the ability to distinguish between British English (en-GB) and American English (en-US) formats. This ensures dates, times, and other regional formatting align with your preferences.</p>
<p><strong>ℹ️ Area information at your fingertips</strong></p>
<p>We've added quick access to area details in the booking overview. Simply click the area's info button to view the area's description and timezone. This makes it easier to understand the context of your bookings without navigating away from the overview.</p>
<p><strong>🔧 Administrator improvements</strong></p>
<p>For organization administrators, we've rolled out several enhancements to streamline user and area management:</p>
<ul>
<li class="">First and last names for users: You can now specify first and last names for users in the system, providing better clarity in user management.</li>
<li class="">Mobile-optimized admin navigation: The navigation bar in the Admin UI has been optimized for mobile devices, making it easier to manage your organization on the go.</li>
<li class="">Default timezone visibility: When editing an area, the organization's default timezone is now displayed, helping you make informed decisions about area timezone settings.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>📋 More details</strong></p>
<p>As always, you can find detailed information about all recent releases and technical changes on our <a href="https://github.com/seatsurfing/seatsurfing/releases" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">GitHub releases page</a>.</p>
<p><em>Ready to transform your workplace with smart desk booking? <a class="" href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/sign-up">Get started with Seatsurfing today for free</a> or <a class="" href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/contact">get in touch with us</a>.</em></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jan</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/janjonas</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="news" term="news"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[30-day free trial for Seatsurfing Professional now available]]></title>
        <id>https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/free-trial-professional</id>
        <link href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/free-trial-professional"/>
        <updated>2025-10-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We're excited to announce that our Professional Plan is now available with a 30-day free trial. This means you can explore all the enterprise features that help growing teams manage desk sharing and space booking efficiently – without any commitment.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We're excited to announce that our Professional Plan is now available with a 30-day free trial. This means you can explore all the enterprise features that help growing teams manage desk sharing and space booking efficiently – without any commitment.</p>
<p>Getting started with your 30-day trial is simple:</p>
<ul>
<li class=""><strong>New to Seatsurfing?</strong> <a class="" href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/sign-up?paid">Simply sign up for a Professional Plan</a> account and your trial begins immediately.</li>
<li class=""><strong>Already using Seatsurfing?</strong> Existing users can activate the trial directly in the admin area under the "Subscription" section. No need to create a new account.</li>
</ul>
<p>To continue using all Professional Plan features beyond the 30-day trial, admins need to subscribe before the trial period ends. If you choose not to subscribe, your account will automatically convert to the Free Plan after 30 days. You can continue using Seatsurfing at no cost with up to 10 users and access to a <a class="" href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/features">limited features set</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jan</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/janjonas</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="news" term="news"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[September '25 news]]></title>
        <id>https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/news-september-2025</id>
        <link href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/news-september-2025"/>
        <updated>2025-09-06T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We're happy to share some updates that have rolled out over the past few weeks. These improvements are part of our ongoing commitment to making Seatsurfing a great workplace management solution for teams of all sizes.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We're happy to share some updates that have rolled out over the past few weeks. These improvements are part of our ongoing commitment to making Seatsurfing a great workplace management solution for teams of all sizes.</p>
<p><strong>🌍 German website launch</strong></p>
<p>Our website is now available in German at <a href="https://seatsurfing.io/de" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">https://seatsurfing.io/de</a>.</p>
<p><strong>🏢 Introducing our Enterprise plan</strong></p>
<p>Our Enterprise plan is designed for organizations with 500 or more users. This plan includes dedicated hosting options in Germany, Finland, or the USA. This ensures optimal performance and maximum data protection. Check out all the details on our updated <a class="" href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/pricing/">pricing page</a>.</p>
<p><strong>🎧 New support portal</strong></p>
<p>We've launched our dedicated support portal at <a href="https://support.seatsurfing.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">https://support.seatsurfing.io</a> for all general inquiries and technical support requests. Professional and Enterprise plan customers can expect responses within 24 hours.</p>
<p><strong>📧 Enhanced onboarding experience</strong></p>
<p>We've enhanced our onboarding process for new customers on both Free, Professional and Enterprise plans. After creating your account, you'll receive a series of helpful emails over your first few days to guide you through setup, share best practices, and help you get the most out of Seatsurfing.</p>
<p><strong>🔧 Platform updates and bug fixes</strong></p>
<p>Our development team has rolled out several platform updates focused on stability and performance improvements. You can find detailed information about all recent releases on our <a href="https://github.com/seatsurfing/seatsurfing/releases" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">GitHub releases page</a>.</p>
<p><strong>💝 Refreshed GitHub sponsorship</strong></p>
<p>We've updated our GitHub Sponsorship page! Visit <a href="https://github.com/sponsors/seatsurfing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">https://github.com/sponsors/seatsurfing</a> to learn more about supporting our open-source project.</p>
<p><strong>📬 Dedicated contact channels</strong></p>
<p>We now have dedicated email addresses for specific types of inquiries:</p>
<ul>
<li class="">Support requests: <a href="mailto:support@seatsurfing.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">support@seatsurfing.io</a></li>
<li class="">Security concerns: <a href="mailto:security@seatsurfing.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">security@seatsurfing.io</a></li>
</ul>
<p><em>Ready to transform your workplace with smart desk booking? <a class="" href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/sign-up">Get started with Seatsurfing today for free</a> or <a class="" href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/contact">get in touch with us</a>.</em></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jan</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/janjonas</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="news" term="news"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[End of Life Announcement: Seatsurfing for Confluence Server and Data Center Support]]></title>
        <id>https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/discontinuation-confluence-server-dc</id>
        <link href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/discontinuation-confluence-server-dc"/>
        <updated>2025-07-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Effective October 15, 2025, we will be discontinuing support for the app “Seatsurfing for Confluence” in Confluence Server and Confluence Data Center environments.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Effective <strong>October 15, 2025</strong>, we will be discontinuing support for the app “Seatsurfing for Confluence” in Confluence Server and Confluence Data Center environments.</p>
<p>Please note: This change only affects Confluence Server and Confluence Data Center environments. Our <a href="https://marketplace.atlassian.com/apps/1224242/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">Confluence Cloud version</a> app remains fully supported and will continue to receive updates and new features. We are focusing our development efforts on enhancing the Cloud experience to better serve our users' evolving needs. We'll be sharing more details about the upcoming features in the near future.</p>
<p>Please contact us at <a href="mailto:hello@seatsurfing.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">hello@seatsurfing.io</a> if you have any questions about this discontinuation or need assistance.</p>
<p>The Confluence Cloud integration is available for all customers on our free and paid hosted cloud plans. Not subscribed yet? <a class="" href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/sign-up">Easily get started for free</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jan</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/janjonas</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="news" term="news"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seatsurfing 1.36: Recurring bookings are here]]></title>
        <id>https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/seatsurfing-1-36-released</id>
        <link href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/seatsurfing-1-36-released"/>
        <updated>2025-06-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We're happy to announce the availability of Seatsurfing version 1.36. This release adds recurring bookings. Users can now book their favorite spots weekly or monthly with just one click. Whether you prefer the same desk every Tuesday or need your usual spot for the entire next week, you can now set it once and let Seatsurfing handle the rest.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We're happy to announce the availability of Seatsurfing version 1.36. This release adds recurring bookings. Users can now book their favorite spots weekly or monthly with just one click. Whether you prefer the same desk every Tuesday or need your usual spot for the entire next week, you can now set it once and let Seatsurfing handle the rest.</p>
<p>Here's what changed in Seatsurfing 1.36 since the release of Seatsurfing 1.34:</p>
<ul>
<li class="">Feature: Recurring bookings</li>
<li class="">Feature: Performance improvements (caching of settings and static web exports)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Read-only and read-write service accounts</li>
<li class="">Various bug fixes</li>
<li class="">Updated dependencies</li>
</ul>
<p>Customers on our Free hosted cloud plans need to upgrade as recurring bookings are a <a class="" href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/features">Professional feature</a>. Not subscribed yet? <a class="" href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/sign-up">Easily get started for free</a>.</p>
<p>Self-hosting users can find the source code of version 1.36 on <a href="https://github.com/seatsurfing/seatsurfing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">GitHub</a> and should carefully review the <strong>breaking changes warning</strong> in the <a href="https://github.com/seatsurfing/seatsurfing/releases/tag/v1.36.0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">release notes</a> before upgrading. Pre-built Docker images can be pulled from the <a href="https://github.com/orgs/seatsurfing/packages?repo_name=seatsurfing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">GitHub Container Registry</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jan</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/janjonas</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="release" term="release"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seatsurfing now available as Microsoft Teams App]]></title>
        <id>https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/seatsurfing-msteams-announcement</id>
        <link href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/seatsurfing-msteams-announcement"/>
        <updated>2025-06-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We're excited to announce that Seatsurfing is now available as a Microsoft Teams app in the Microsoft AppSource marketplace! This integration brings workspace booking directly into the Microsoft Teams environment your team already knows and loves.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We're excited to announce that Seatsurfing is now available as a Microsoft Teams app in the Microsoft AppSource marketplace! This integration brings workspace booking directly into the Microsoft Teams environment your team already knows and loves.</p>
<p>The new Seatsurfing Teams app eliminates the need to switch between different platforms throughout your workday. Whether you're planning your week, booking a desk for tomorrow, or checking availability for a meeting, everything is now accessible right within Microsoft Teams.</p>
<p>To get started visit the <a href="https://appsource.microsoft.com/en-us/product/office/WA200008773" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">Microsoft AppSource marketplace</a>, install the app for free and enable the Microsoft Teams integration as outlined in <a class="" href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/docs/msteams">our documentation</a>.</p>
<p>The Microsoft Teams integration is available for all customers on our Free and Professional hosted cloud plans. Not subscribed yet? <a class="" href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/sign-up">Easily get started for free</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Jan</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/janjonas</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="news" term="news"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seatsurfing 1.34 released]]></title>
        <id>https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/seatsurfing-1-34-released</id>
        <link href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/seatsurfing-1-34-released"/>
        <updated>2025-06-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today we've released Seatsurfing version 1.34. The new version improves the way users can navigate floor plans, introduces the specification of subjects when placing bookings, and adds technical Service Accounts.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we've released Seatsurfing version 1.34. The new version improves the way users can navigate floor plans, introduces the specification of subjects when placing bookings, and adds technical Service Accounts.</p>
<p>Here's what changed in Seatsurfing 1.34 since the release of Seatsurfing 1.32:</p>
<ul>
<li class="">Feature: New and intuitive way of navigating the map using Zoom-Pan-Pinch in the Booking UI</li>
<li class="">Feature: Option for mandatory booking subjects per space</li>
<li class="">Feature: New user role "Service Account", meant to calling REST APIs programmatically</li>
<li class="">Feature: New environment variables PUBLIC_SCHEME and PUBLIC_PORT to support non-standard (HTTPS port 443) setups</li>
<li class="">Various bug fixes</li>
<li class="">Updated dependencies</li>
</ul>
<p>Customers on our Free and Professional hosted cloud plans always enjoy the latest versions automatically. Not subscribed yet? <a class="" href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/sign-up">Easily get started for free</a>.</p>
<p>Self-hosting users can find the source code of version 1.34 on <a href="https://github.com/seatsurfing/seatsurfing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">GitHub</a>. Pre-built Docker images can be pulled from the <a href="https://github.com/orgs/seatsurfing/packages?repo_name=seatsurfing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">GitHub Container Registry</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Heiner</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/virtualzone</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="release" term="release"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seatsurfing 1.32 released]]></title>
        <id>https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/seatsurfing-1-32-released</id>
        <link href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/seatsurfing-1-32-released"/>
        <updated>2025-05-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We're happy to announce the availability of Seatsurfing version 1.32. Everything in this new version is about groups: You can now organize your users in groups. These groups can be used as approvers for your spaces, i.e. a space admin in a space's approver group must approve a user's booking request before it becomes definite. Furthermore, you can use groups to restrict users who can book specific spaces, i.e. only users in an allowed group are permitted to place a booking.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We're happy to announce the availability of Seatsurfing version 1.32. Everything in this new version is about groups: You can now organize your users in groups. These groups can be used as approvers for your spaces, i.e. a space admin in a space's approver group must approve a user's booking request before it becomes definite. Furthermore, you can use groups to restrict users who can book specific spaces, i.e. only users in an allowed group are permitted to place a booking.</p>
<p>Here's what changed in Seatsurfing 1.32 since the release of Seatsurfing 1.31:</p>
<ul>
<li class="">Feature: Organize users in groups</li>
<li class="">Feature: Specify approver and allowed booker groups per space</li>
<li class="">Feature: Approve bookings</li>
<li class="">Feature: Restrict space-booking by group memberships</li>
<li class="">Various bug fixes</li>
<li class="">Updated dependencies</li>
</ul>
<p>Customers on our Free and Professional hosted cloud plans always enjoy the latest versions automatically. Not subscribed yet? <a class="" href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/sign-up">Easily get started for free</a>.</p>
<p>Self-hosting users can find the source code of version 1.32 on <a href="https://github.com/seatsurfing/seatsurfing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">GitHub</a>. Pre-built Docker images can be pulled from the <a href="https://github.com/orgs/seatsurfing/packages?repo_name=seatsurfing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">GitHub Container Registry</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Heiner</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/virtualzone</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="release" term="release"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seatsurfing 1.31 released]]></title>
        <id>https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/seatsurfing-1-31-released</id>
        <link href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/seatsurfing-1-31-released"/>
        <updated>2025-05-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We're happy to announce the availability of Seatsurfing version 1.31. The new version lets users import their bookings into their calendar applications (such as Microsoft Outlook, Apple Calendar, Google Mail etc.) using the Booking Web Interface. Additionally, users can opt for receiving booking confirmations via email, and these emails also include an attachment which can be imported to calendars in no time. By the way, we're now sending emails in HTML formatting, providing a greater user experience.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We're happy to announce the availability of Seatsurfing version 1.31. The new version lets users import their bookings into their calendar applications (such as Microsoft Outlook, Apple Calendar, Google Mail etc.) using the Booking Web Interface. Additionally, users can opt for receiving booking confirmations via email, and these emails also include an attachment which can be imported to calendars in no time. By the way, we're now sending emails in HTML formatting, providing a greater user experience.</p>
<p>Here's what changed in Seatsurfing 1.31 since the release of Seatsurfing 1.28:</p>
<ul>
<li class="">Feature: Add ability to download iCalendar (.ics) events from Booking UI (1.30)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Add email booking confirmations per user opt-in in Booking UI (1.31)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Add support for HTML emails (1.31)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Add email footer support (1.31)</li>
<li class="">Various bug fixes</li>
<li class="">Updated dependencies</li>
</ul>
<p>Customers on our Free and Professional hosted cloud plans always enjoy the latest versions automatically. Not subscribed yet? <a class="" href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/sign-up">Easily get started for free</a>.</p>
<p>Self-hosting users can find the source code of version 1.31 on <a href="https://github.com/seatsurfing/seatsurfing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">GitHub</a>. Pre-built Docker images can be pulled from the <a href="https://github.com/orgs/seatsurfing/packages?repo_name=seatsurfing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">GitHub Container Registry</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Heiner</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/virtualzone</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="release" term="release"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cloud-hosted Professional plan launched]]></title>
        <id>https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/cloud-saas-paid-plan-launched</id>
        <link href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/cloud-saas-paid-plan-launched"/>
        <updated>2025-04-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many of you, our users, asked us for. Today, we are excited to finally announce the launch and immediate availability of our cloud-hosted Professional plan 🤩]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Many of you, our users, asked us for. Today, we are excited to finally announce the launch and immediate availability of our cloud-hosted Professional plan 🤩</p>
<p>The Professional plan includes all features known from the Open Source Edition of Seatsurfing, plus:</p>
<ul class="fa-ul"><li><span class="fa-li"><i class="fa-solid fa-circle-check"></i></span> Carefree Software as a Service (Saas) hosting on fast servers located in Germany</li><li><span class="fa-li"><i class="fa-solid fa-circle-check"></i></span> As many users as you need (pay per user)</li><li><span class="fa-li"><i class="fa-solid fa-circle-check"></i></span> Add your organization's custom domain to access your Seatsurfing instance</li><li><span class="fa-li"><i class="fa-solid fa-circle-check"></i></span> 24/7 premium support</li><li><span class="fa-li"><i class="fa-solid fa-circle-check"></i></span> Monthly payment</li><li><span class="fa-li"><i class="fa-solid fa-circle-check"></i></span> …and there's more to come!</li></ul>
<p>Of course, the Open Source Edition will still be the basis of the Professional plan. This is why you can expect regular updates, enhancements and new features.</p>
<p>Moreover, we will continue to provide the Cloud-hosted Free plan, which will remain cost-free for up to ten users. Perfectly suited to give Seatsurfing a try or to provide desk sharing, room reservations and other kinds of "space bookings" to small organizations.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="you-are-already-subscribed-to-the-free-plan-and-want-to-upgrade">You are already subscribed to the Free plan and want to upgrade?<a href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/cloud-saas-paid-plan-launched#you-are-already-subscribed-to-the-free-plan-and-want-to-upgrade" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur You are already subscribed to the Free plan and want to upgrade?" title="Direkter Link zur You are already subscribed to the Free plan and want to upgrade?" translate="no">​</a></h4>
<p>Just log in to your organizations' administration web-interface, navigate to "Subscription" and upgrade in no time.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorTargetStickyNavbar_Vzrq" id="you-are-new-to-seatsurfing-and-want-to-sign-up">You are new to Seatsurfing and want to sign up?<a href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/cloud-saas-paid-plan-launched#you-are-new-to-seatsurfing-and-want-to-sign-up" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direkter Link zur You are new to Seatsurfing and want to sign up?" title="Direkter Link zur You are new to Seatsurfing and want to sign up?" translate="no">​</a></h4>
<p>Create a new account and have your Seatsurfing instance ready within seconds:</p>
<a href="https://seatsurfing.io/sign-up" class="button button--primary button--lg button-gradient">Get it free</a>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Heiner</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/virtualzone</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="hosting" term="hosting"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fast forward - from Seatsurfing 1.21 to 1.29]]></title>
        <id>https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/seatsurfing-1-29-released</id>
        <link href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/seatsurfing-1-29-released"/>
        <updated>2025-04-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The past weeks ran fast: We've released eight new versions (plus multiple fix versions) of Seatsurfing, each containing exciting new features. Features which our users asked for. As we've not blogged about versions 1.22 to 1.28, this blog post summarized the most remarkable features and improvements since the release of version 1.21 which was released by the end of 2024.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The past weeks ran fast: We've released eight new versions (plus multiple fix versions) of Seatsurfing, each containing exciting new features. Features which our users asked for. As we've not blogged about versions 1.22 to 1.28, this blog post summarized the most remarkable features and improvements since the release of version 1.21 which was released by the end of 2024.</p>
<p>Here's what changed in Seatsurfing 1.29 since the release of Seatsurfing 1.21:</p>
<ul>
<li class="">Feature: Add Estonian translation for Booking UI (1.28)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Add ability to assign attributes to spaces in Admin UI (1.27)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Show and search for space attributes in Booking UI (1.27)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Add Azure Communication Services (ACS) as alternative to SMTP for sending mails (1.26)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Cloud hosted Seatsurfing adds individual subdomains and custom domains (1.25)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Sse real email address as username (1.25)</li>
<li class="">Feature: ARIA labels to Booking UI form for improved accessibility (1.25)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Allow to cancel your bookings directly from the map (1.23)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Connect your calendar via CalDAV and keep track of your space bookings (1.22)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Add filtering options for Number of spaces, Number of free spaces and Buddies on site (1.22)</li>
<li class="">Improvement: Make language changes persistent (1.28)</li>
<li class="">Improvement: Display version on preferences page in Admin UI (1.28)</li>
<li class="">Improvement: Optimize language handling in Admin and Booking UI (1.27)</li>
<li class="">Improvement: Perform database schema updates more resilient (1.26)</li>
<li class="">Improvement: Support PostgreSQL &lt; v16 (1.26)</li>
<li class="">Improvement: Sdd auth provider template for Okta (1.26)</li>
<li class="">Improvement: Improve password reset process (1.25)</li>
<li class="">Improvement: List user bookings according to location's timezone (1.24)</li>
<li class="">Improvement: Create/verify JWT Access Tokens with asymmetric RSA algorithm (1.24)</li>
<li class="">Improvement: Optimized date formatting (1.22)</li>
<li class="">Improvement: Added Content Security Policy (CSP) to the frontends (1.22)</li>
<li class="">Various bug fixes</li>
<li class="">Updated dependencies</li>
</ul>
<p>As usual, you can find the source code of version 1.29 on <a href="https://github.com/seatsurfing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">GitHub</a>. Pre-built Docker images can be pulled from the <a href="https://github.com/seatsurfing?tab=packages&amp;repo_name=backend" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">GitHub Container Registry</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Heiner</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/virtualzone</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="release" term="release"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seatsurfing 1.21 released]]></title>
        <id>https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/seatsurfing-1-21-released</id>
        <link href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/seatsurfing-1-21-released"/>
        <updated>2024-12-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Time for some release news! Seatsurfing 1.21 has been released today, including several features that you, Seatsurfing's users, asked for. The biggest feature is that you can now specify custom attributes which can be attached to your locations. For example, as an administrator, you can specify whether a location is accessible with wheelchairs or what kind of media system is installed. Your users can view a location's attributes and even filter the list of locations according to their needs.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Time for some release news! Seatsurfing 1.21 has been released today, including several features that you, Seatsurfing's users, asked for. The biggest feature is that you can now specify custom attributes which can be attached to your locations. For example, as an administrator, you can specify whether a location is accessible with wheelchairs or what kind of media system is installed. Your users can view a location's attributes and even filter the list of locations according to their needs.</p>
<p>Enjoy the new features, I wish you a happy new year 2025!</p>
<p>Here's what changed in Seatsurfing 1.21 since the release of Seatsurfing 1.19:</p>
<ul>
<li class="">Feature: Added support for location attributes and filters (1.21)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Added ability to (temporarily) disable locations (1.21)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Added optional OAuth2 / OpenID Connect Logout URL (1.21)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Added missing Italian translations to Booking UI (1.21)</li>
<li class="">Feature: New setting for minimum booking duration, defaults to 0 (1.20)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Support for partially booked seats (1.20)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Support for custom logo (1.20)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Added "Disable buddies" setting (1.20)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Added maximum hours before cancellation setting (1.20)</li>
<li class="">Improvement: Reduce leave time by one second automatically to avoid non-existing overlaps (1.20)</li>
<li class="">Improvement: Always show search box at the bottom in Booking UI (1.20)</li>
<li class="">Updated dependencies</li>
</ul>
<p>As usual, you can find the source code of version 1.21 on <a href="https://github.com/seatsurfing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">GitHub</a>. Pre-built Docker images can be pulled from the <a href="https://github.com/seatsurfing?tab=packages&amp;repo_name=backend" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">GitHub Container Registry</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Heiner</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/virtualzone</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="release" term="release"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seatsurfing 1.19 released]]></title>
        <id>https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/seatsurfing-1-19-released</id>
        <link href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/seatsurfing-1-19-released"/>
        <updated>2024-08-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Long time no hear! While we've released several new versions of Seatsurfing since the last post from August 2023, we haven't blogged about them. Let's catch up with today's release of Seatsurfing 1.19.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Long time no hear! While we've released several new versions of Seatsurfing since the last post from August 2023, we haven't blogged about them. Let's catch up with today's release of Seatsurfing 1.19.</p>
<p>Here are some of the awesome new features: You can now quickly access certain floors and spaces by direct links / QR codes. A brand-new slider allows for quickly getting an overview of the space availability in the upcoming days. Space admins can manually add and edit reservations for their users. Find out where your buddies sit at a glance. Furthermore, multiple translations made it into the new version - namely Hebrew, Romanian, Hungarian, and Dutch.</p>
<p>Here's what changed in Seatsurfing 1.19 since the release of Seatsurfing 1.14:</p>
<ul>
<li class="">Feature: Added slider to get a quick overview of the week (1.19)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Floor and space URLs can be accessed by direct links / QR codes (1.19)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Hebrew translation for Booking and Admin UI (1.19)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Romanian translation for Booking UI (1.19)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Hungarian translation for the Booking UI (1.18)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Dutch translation (1.16)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Implemented no-admin-restrictions feature (1.18)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Edit and create booking in Admin UI (1.18)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Hovering over desks shows a tooltip to see who is sitting there (1.17)</li>
<li class="">Feature: See each buddy's next booking (1.17)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Add buddy by email (1.17)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Add your buddies and highlight their seats (1.16)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Add support for desk coloring preferences (1.16)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Added support for ghcr.io (1.16)</li>
<li class="">Feature: Add user concurrency limit setting (1.15)</li>
<li class="">Improvement: Improved icon alignment (1.19)</li>
<li class="">Improvement: Refactored Docker Builds (1.18)</li>
<li class="">Fix: Switch to summer / winter time not handled correctly (1.15)</li>
<li class="">Fix: Incorrect date / time format (1.15)</li>
<li class="">Updated dependencies (1.19)</li>
</ul>
<p>As usual, you can find the source code of version 1.19 on <a href="https://github.com/seatsurfing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">GitHub</a>. Pre-built Docker images can be pulled from the <a href="https://github.com/seatsurfing?tab=packages&amp;repo_name=backend" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">GitHub Container Registry</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Heiner</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/virtualzone</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="release" term="release"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seatsurfing 1.14 released]]></title>
        <id>https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/seatsurfing-1-14-released</id>
        <link href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/seatsurfing-1-14-released"/>
        <updated>2023-08-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We're happy to announce the availability of Seatsurfing 1.14. Version 1.14 adds Italian translations and the ability for users to change their own password. Besides, various improvements and fixes have been implemented.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We're happy to announce the availability of Seatsurfing 1.14. Version 1.14 adds Italian translations and the ability for users to change their own password. Besides, various improvements and fixes have been implemented.</p>
<p>Here's what changed in Seatsurfing 1.14 since the release of Seatsurfing 1.13:</p>
<ul>
<li class="">Feature: Added Italian translation</li>
<li class="">Feature: Ability to change own password in Booking UI</li>
<li class="">Improvement: Upgraded dependencies</li>
<li class="">Fix: Changing a super admin's properties in Admin UI resets super admin's role</li>
<li class="">Fix: Prevent logging in to Admin UI as a regular user</li>
<li class="">Fix: Access /ui and /admin without trailing slash</li>
<li class="">Fix: Fixed date picker not shown correctly in daily booking mode</li>
<li class="">Fix: Fixed broken Admin UI translations</li>
<li class="">Fix: Incorrect redirects in admin and booking UI</li>
<li class="">Fix: Language auto-detection not working / partly translated texts</li>
<li class="">Fix: Missing minimum length check when changing a user's password using the Admin UI</li>
<li class="">Fix: Added missing login attempt recordings so that anonymous Confluence users are not deleted immediately</li>
</ul>
<p>As usual, you can find the source code of version 1.14 on <a href="https://github.com/seatsurfing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">GitHub</a> and pre-built Docker images on <a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/seatsurfing/backend" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">Docker Hub</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Heiner</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/virtualzone</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="release" term="release"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seatsurfing 1.13 released]]></title>
        <id>https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/seatsurfing-1-13-released</id>
        <link href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/seatsurfing-1-13-released"/>
        <updated>2023-05-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A few days ago, we've released Seatsurfing 1.13. This new version adds French translations to the user interfaces. Furthermore, we've migrated the React-based front ends from Create React App (CRA) to Next.js. The move to Next.js allows for server-side rendering, resulting in faster load times. However, this leads to a breaking change, because the front ends are not shipped with the backend Docker image anymore, but in two separate containers (admin-ui and booking-ui).]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few days ago, we've released Seatsurfing 1.13. This new version adds French translations to the user interfaces. Furthermore, we've migrated the React-based front ends from Create React App (CRA) to Next.js. The move to Next.js allows for server-side rendering, resulting in faster load times. However, this leads to a breaking change, because the front ends are not shipped with the backend Docker image anymore, but in two separate containers (admin-ui and booking-ui).</p>
<p>Here's what changed in Seatsurfing 1.13 since the release of Seatsurfing 1.12:</p>
<ul>
<li class="">Feature: Migrated Booking UI and Admin UI to Next.js. This leads to a separated Docker containers (front ends not bundled with backend image anymore).</li>
<li class="">Feature: Added French translation</li>
<li class="">Improvement: Upgraded dependencies</li>
<li class="">Fix: Incorrectly formatted SQL query in GetDomains function</li>
</ul>
<p>As usual, you can find the source code of version 1.13 on <a href="https://github.com/seatsurfing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">GitHub</a> and pre-built Docker images on <a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/seatsurfing/backend" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">Docker Hub</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Heiner</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/virtualzone</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="release" term="release"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seatsurfing 1.12 adds user-requested features]]></title>
        <id>https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/seatsurfing-1-12-released</id>
        <link href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/seatsurfing-1-12-released"/>
        <updated>2022-12-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We're pleased to announce the release of Seatsurfing 1.12. The new release adds features our users have requested, such as login brute force prevention, an improved login-process for single-organization instances and more.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We're pleased to announce the release of Seatsurfing 1.12. The new release adds features our users have requested, such as login brute force prevention, an improved login-process for single-organization instances and more.</p>
<p>Here's what changed in Seatsurfing 1.12 since the release of Seatsurfing 1.10:</p>
<ul>
<li class="">Feature: Login brute force prevention</li>
<li class="">Feature: Clean up anonymous confluence users</li>
<li class="">Feature: Improved login process for single-org instances</li>
<li class="">Feature: Make entire map scrollable in Booking UI</li>
<li class="">Feature: Admin UI: Added check for Seatsurfing updates</li>
<li class="">Feature: Booking UI: Improved layout of search config errors</li>
<li class="">Fix: Clear SessionStorage on invalid AccessToken</li>
<li class="">Fix: Fix for security issue</li>
<li class="">Updated dependencies</li>
</ul>
<p>As usual, you can find the source code of version 1.12 on <a href="https://github.com/seatsurfing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">GitHub</a> and pre-built Docker images on <a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/seatsurfing/backend" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">Docker Hub</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Heiner</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/virtualzone</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="release" term="release"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seatsurfing 1.10 replaces native apps with web app]]></title>
        <id>https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/seatsurfing-pwa</id>
        <link href="https://seatsurfing.io/de/blog/seatsurfing-pwa"/>
        <updated>2022-07-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As of July 30, 2022, the Seatsurfing mobile apps for iOS and Android will be discontinued. We decided to focus on one state-of-the-art web booking interface, which is the existing, yet improved Web Booking UI. In order to optimize the user experience of the Web Booking UI when using mobile devices (such as phones and tablets), we've turned it into a Progressive Web App (PWA). This means, you can "install" the web app to your device's home screen and benefit from enhanced caching mechanisms.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As of July 30, 2022, the Seatsurfing mobile apps for iOS and Android will be discontinued. We decided to focus on one state-of-the-art web booking interface, which is the existing, yet improved Web Booking UI. In order to optimize the user experience of the Web Booking UI when using mobile devices (such as phones and tablets), we've turned it into a Progressive Web App (PWA). This means, you can "install" the web app to your device's home screen and benefit from enhanced caching mechanisms.</p>
<p>As usual, you can find the source code of version 1.10 on <a href="https://github.com/seatsurfing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">GitHub</a> and pre-built Docker images on <a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/seatsurfing/backend" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" class="">Docker Hub</a>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Heiner</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/virtualzone</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="release" term="release"/>
    </entry>
</feed>